# M Usman Maqbool Bhutta

#### PHD CANDIDATE · DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRONIC AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING, HKUST, HK

2008 (25), Robotics Institute, 2nd Floor, CYT Building, Lift(35-36), HKUST

□ (+852) 609-44-786 | 🔀 usmanmaqbool@outlook.com | 🌴 usmanmaqbool.github.io | 🖸 UsmanMaqbool | 🛅 usmanmaqbool | 🐧 usmanmaqbool

"Do it with passion or not at all."

### **Summary**

Apart from the research and coding, I'm good in the project management, networking for building teams, writing proposals and presenting ideas. I'm Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises. I've 5+ years of experience specializing in robotics R&D and project management. Current co-founder and COO of a startup which provides indoor navigation services using visible light communication technology [Lisee Technology Corporation Limited Hong Kong]. I have been a part of several other startups related to real estate, marketing, and automation. I'm a simple person who loves entrepreneurship and enjoys to develop the idea to reality.

### **Education**

### The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology - HKUST

(Kowloon, Hong Kong)

Sep. 2016 - Present

- Ph.D. Candidate, RAM-LAB, Robotics Institute, Department of Electronic & Computer Engineering

   PhD Supervisor: **Prof Ming Liu**, Director of Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab (**RAM-LAB**)
- Exchange Supervisor: Prof. Roland Siegwart, Director of Autonomous Systems Lab (ASL), ETH Zürich, Switzerland.
- Exchange Co-Supervisor: Dr. Cesar Dario Cadena Lerma, Senior Researcher at ASL, ETH Zürich, Switzerland.
- Got PEEF CCMS PhD scholarship from Pakistan and overseas research award (ORA).
- · Research: Multi-Agent SLAM System, Place Recognition, Autonomous Car and Deep Learning for automation industry.

### Quaid-i-Azam University - QAU

Islamabad, Pakistan

M.PHIL. ELECTRONICS, DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRONICS

Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

- M.Phil. Supervisor: **Prof Hasan Mahmood**, Department of Electronics, QAU.
- Research: Signal and Image Processing
- Grade: 1st Division (80% Marks)

#### Quaid-i-Azam University - QAU Islamabad, Pakistan

M.Sc. Electronics, Department of Electronics

Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

- 2nd position in batch
- Projects: completed nine projects related to C++, Verilog/HDL and Micro-controller programming.

#### **Bahauddin Zakariya University - BZU**

Multan, Pakistan

B.Sc. in Mathematics and Physics

Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

• Grade: 1st Division

### **Research Publications**

### Multiple Lane Detection Algorithm Based on Optimised Dense Disparity Map Estimation

Conference Paper

Han Ma, Yixin Ma, Jianhao Jiao, M Usman Maqbool Bhutta, Mohammud Junaid Bocus, Lujia Wang, Ming Liu, Rui Fan Accepted in IEEE International Conference on Imaging Systems and Techniques (IST) 2018

Oct 2018

## PCR-Pro: 3D Sparse and Different Scale Point Clouds Registration and Robust Estimation of Information Matrix For Pose Graph SLAM

Conference Paper

M USMAN MAQBOOL BHUTTA, MING LIU

Jul 2018

Presented in IEEE Int. Conf. on CYBER Technology in Automation, Control, and Intelligent Systems, and won **Best Student Paper Finalist Award.** 

## An intelligent approach for robust detection and recognition of multiple color and font styles automobiles license plates: A feature-based algorithm

Conference Paper

M USMAN MAQBOOL BHUTTA, HASAN MAHMOOD, AND HAROON MALIK

Jul 2014

Published in IEEE International Conference on Audio, Language and Image Processing (ICALIP).

Journal Paper

Qamar, Zoha, Bushra Yaseen, and Usman Maqbool

2015

Published in Science International Lahore

**Efficient Reset Design Techniques** 

### **Work Experience**

### **INDUSTRY**

### **Lisee Technology Corporation Limited**

Central, HK Jan 2018 - Present

COO
- Won funding support for company | TSSSU Support HK\$ 300,000 (Jun 19 - May 20).

- Indoor Navigation for Libray using Lisee Technology | PCF Support HK\$ 160,000 (Jun 18 - May 19).

#### **Friends Corporate Technologies**

Islamabad, PK

**CEO** Feb 2013 - Aug 2015

50+ Projects | Electronics/ Electrical Engineering, R&D, image processing, Web Applications Development, MVC Applications

**Federal Government of Pakistan** 

Islamabad, PK

SCIENTIFIC OFFICER May 2012 - Feb 2013

Electronics/ Electrical Engineering, R&D, image processing

Server4Sale, LLC Islamabad, PK

PHP Developer Dec 2009 - Mar 2010

Php web application development for Joomla and Zend frameworks.

#### **ACADEMIC**

### **Department of Computer Science**

BZU sub campus Sahiwal, PK

LECTURER (VISITING)

Feb 2016 - Jun 2016

Teaching MCS and BS-CS courses

### **Department of Physics**

Government PG College Sahiwal, PK

CTI Aug. 2015 - Apr. 2016

Teaching BS physics (Electronics related courses + Labs + Projects)

### **Honors & Awards**

#### INTERNATIONAL

July 2018	<b>Best Student Paper Finalist Award</b> , IEEE Int. Conf. on CYBER Technology in Automation, Control, and	Tianjin, China
	Intelligent Systems	Harijiri, China
May, 2018	Best Proposal Audience Award, Campus Challenge - Transportation, HKUST	HKUST, HK
Nov, 2017	Best Mapper Award, Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab, HKUST	Shenzhen, China
May, 2017	Completion Award, The Graduate Teaching Assistant Training, HKUST	HKUST, HK
Dec, 2016	Best External Award, Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab, HKUST	Shenzhen, China
Nov, 2016	Completion Award, Author Workshop, Elsevier Publishing Campus	HKUST, HK

### DOMESTIC

DOMESTIC				
Sep 2016	<b>CCMS PhD Scholarship</b> , Won Chief Minister Marit Scholarship (CCMS) scholarship award by Punjab Government (PEEF), Pakistan for pursuing my PhD studies at HKUST, HK	Lahore, PK		
Sep 2013	Participant, Painting for peace (Pakistan-India-Afghanistan) event, a part of the Harmony initiative	Islamabad, PK		
Apr 2013	Participant, Case Spark in business plan competition	Islamabad, PK		
Apr 2013	Participant, Case EPICA	Islamabad, PK		
Apr 2013	Participant, How to be a Better Playwright Workshop by PNCA and US Embassay Pakistan	Islamabad, PK		
Oct 2012	Participant, Punjab Youth Festival	Lahore, PK		
Oct 2011	Participant, Int'l Youth Conference and Festival	Islamabad, PK		
Sep 2011	Participant, Asian Youth Conference and Peace Festival	Lahore, PK		
Apr 2011	<b>Completion Award,</b> Acting and Directing Theater Workshop by PNCA and US Embassay Pakistan	Islamabad, PK		
Dec 2011	Participant, National Drama Festival	Islamabad, PK		
Dec 2010	<b>Instuctor of short Course</b> , PHP Web Development' at the Department of Electronics, QAU	Islamabad, PK		
Apr 2013	Completion Award, Running River Rafting course by Adventure Foundation of Pakistan	Mansehra, PK		
Apr 2013	Completion Award, Paragliding course by QAU Adventure Club	Islamabad, PK		
Dec 2008	Award of Honor, Finance Secretary of Electronics Student Society (ESS) at QAU	Islamabad, PK		

### **Academic Activities**

ICRA	Referee Service, IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Robotics and Automation	2020
Spr 2019	<b>Teaching Assistant</b> , EESM 5547 - Multimedia Signal Processing	HKUST, HK
CASE	Referee Service, IEEE International Conference on Automation Science and Engineering	2019
IROS	<b>Referee Service</b> , IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems	2019, 2018
Fall 2018	Teaching Assistant, ELEC4820 - Medical Imaging	HKUST, HK
Spr 2018	<b>Teaching Assistant</b> , EESM 5547 - Multimedia Signal Processing	HKUST, HK
Spr 2017	<b>Teaching Assistant</b> , ELEC 1010 - Electronic and Information Technology	HKUST, HK